Ravgeet Dhillon

Software Engineer and Technical Content Writer with over 4+ years of experience who has worked with startups and open-source organizations across the globe. An individual with a teacher and student mindset. Interested in a 100% remote role. Based in India (UTC+05:30).

Email: ravgeetdhillon,@gmail.com, LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ravgeetdhillon, GitHub: gitHub.com/ravgeetdhillon, Website: ravgeet.in, Blog: blog.ravgeet.in

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer and Founder - RavSam, India - May 2020 - Present

- Founded a Full Stack Development agency (ravsam.in) along with my father, and served clients with Web, Mobile, CMS, APIs, Automation, and DevOps services.
- Secured one year contract with CloudAnswers to provide Custom Software Development and Consultancy in Jamstack technologies (React.js, Next.js, Firebase).
- Worked on Web and Flutter app for Organic Farmers Connect which made the headlines in local newspapers.
- Key achievement: Learned about management, sales, and other aspects of running a small startup.

Software Engineer & Technical Content Writer - Freelance, Remote - May 2018 - Present

- Working on a contract basis with Draft.dev and Honeybadger to create, review and edit technical content related to React.js, Vue.js,
 Serverless, Python, and other Jamstack technologies, consumed by 1,000,000+ readers.
- Writing detailed guides, howtos, tutorials for ATA, CSS Tricks, Vonage, Twilio, Strapi, and many more companies and showcasing the integration of their platforms with other tools and frameworks.
- Told by an editor, "You wrote so well, I'm tempted to use it on my own machine".
- Key achievement: Learned about different tools and frameworks and devised a model for networking and getting work opportunities.

Full Stack Developer Intern – Techies Infotech, India – January 2020 - May 2020

- Designed websites based on Jamstack architecture which reduced the build times by 30% and increased PageSpeed scores to 90+.
- Architected Laravel websites for better code structure which decreased the feature development time by 20%.
- Key achievement: Got promoted to Intern Team Lead and lead a team of 4 interns in their assignments.

Google Summer of Code Developer - GNOME Foundation, Remote - February 2019 - August 2019

- Redesigned the GTK's official website product and documentation using Bootstrap by keeping accessibility in mind.
- Migrated the legacy PHP codebase to Jekyll for Static Site Generation and implemented a Git-based CMS for non-technical contributors.
- Setup deployment of the website using Gitlab CI/CD to make the new changes live in under two minutes.
- Key achievement: Made it is easy for non-technical individuals to contribute to an open-source project.

EDUCATION

B. Tech CSE – Guru Nanak Dev University, Amritsar – AUGUST 2016 - JULY 2020

- Served as the Technical Head of the Computer Engineering Student Society in 2019.
- Co-organized Polaris Tech Fest 2019 and various workshops related to Web Development and Open Source.

SKILLS

Frontend: React.js, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Jekyll, Redux, Vuex, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, UI/UX

Backend: Strapi, Laravel, Node.js, Express, Flask, Django, Rest APIs

Languages: Python, Javascript, Typescript, Dart, PHP

Mobile: Flutter, Firebase, Provider

Database: MySQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, RDBMS

Hosting & DevOps: Netlify, Vercel, Github Actions, Heroku, Gitlab CI/CD, Codemagic, VPS, Nginx Addons: Figma, Stripe, Slack, Notion, Markdown, Trello, Automation, CMS, Agile

Development: Linux Ubuntu, GitHub, VSCode, Prettier, Webpack, ESLint

PROJECTS

Metafold Store: A Strapi/Node.js powered E-Commerce website with customer and admin portals, built in Vue/Nuxt.js and deployed on Netlify and Hostinger VPS.

Brandcares: A Flutter app with Provider state management, connected to a Laravel powered backend, published on Play Store and App Store. The app allows users to detect and report product and copyright infringements.

Notify Slack Github Action: A GitHub Action to send a Slack Notification whenever a Github Action completes with success, warnings, or failure.

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Curating a monthly, dev-related, and personal stories newsletter with 300+ subscribers.
- Developed and launched Notion Feeder and acquired 100+ customers in the first 80 days.
- Runners Up at Smart India Hackathon 2019 for creating a Python-based app that solves the traffic situation at toll booths in India.